<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diary on Lithos&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diary on Lithos&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:49:58 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title># 《牧羊人》</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sheperd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:49:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sheperd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;牧羊人是个精明人，他总是能从羊群身上获得最多价值。冬天，羊长出很多毛，他就把大半的毛都剃掉，薄利多销地卖与人。因为价格实惠，人们都赞不绝口，经常从他那里进货。但牧羊人告诉羊群这些毛是为了实现羊群富足的必要牺牲，他永远以羊群利益至上。之所以要把毛交给牧羊人是因为他是羊群的主心骨，带领羊群走向温饱。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title># River Town: the Metaphor of Chapter VI. ‘Storm’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/river_town/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:49:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/river_town/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Chapter six of River Town, the metaphor of &amp;ldquo;storm&amp;rdquo; is incredibly ingenious, much like the line from &lt;em&gt;Border Town&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;The heavy rain washed everything, yet it washed away nothing.&amp;rdquo; True, storms rinsed both HongKong and Fuling the night of HongKong’s handover to China. Yet only when people, like Andy in &lt;em&gt;The Shawshank Redemption&lt;/em&gt;, allow the rain to cleanse the blockages and stubbornness deep within their souls, and reach their arms out to the sky, can they attain true liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title># Grassroot HongKong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yaumatei/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 09:08:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yaumatei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is HongKong? What is it in its pure form, in a most representative phrase, in just words without bias? No other place dare to utter before YauMaTei makes its point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I find myself always agitated to be surrounded by old, down-to-earth, and perhaps dusty, dirty alleyways. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about the unique historic scent. Yet, still worth mentioning, the old city wall of Peking and the brick-stone alleys in Shanghai have been mostly arbitrarily wiped out, which makes this block in HongKong appears to be a solitary time-space isolated from the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
